I've played every
Assassin's Creed game and I think the franchise peaked with the mobile game. It was all downhill from there.
The most revolutionary thing the Assassin's Creed franchise
introduced it was fans never being happy. Something games like Destiny
also did and Call of Duty introduced in later instalments.
The first game was pitched back in 2003 when Ubisoft Montreal said:
"I'm tired of making games about an Iranian dude running on walls!"
We need something completely different. Like an Arabian dude running on walls. So they did that
Assassin's Creed, no subtitle. The second Assassin's Creed was released in
2007. A completely open living world. This will never be an overused concept
It takes place during the Third Crusade but every game as a modern part. In the distant future of
2012, a life-saving company named Abstergo has invented a machine that lets you relive your ancestors memory.
It's the nastiest sex toy I don't even- They asked aa guy named Desmond Miles to help them with the research-
involuntarily and he's an asshole about it
We've been kidnapped *gibberish* torture- Shut up! You get to witness
Medieval Jerusalem, and it smells. And not everything can be perfect.
A thousand-year war has been fought between Templars who invented modern banking and
Assassins who kill people and see what happens. For some reason Templars are winning. Main character is Altair
He's an assassin and his boss has ordered him to hunt down nine cartoon villains. When the last guy is dead,
Plot twist!
His boss was also a cartoon villain.
Then the game completely spirals because the boss has a piece of Eden a powerful object that can create
Illusions, maybe create some real armor instead? The end. Back in current day, Desmond's getting executed!
Kristen Bell stops them, then he walks around the office and there's symbols predicting the end of the world 2012.
Assassin's Creed has aged like brown bread. It was passable when it came out, but now it's moldy and will make you puke.
Assassin's Creed 2
Because the first game wasn't fantastic, they could make a game that was better in every single way.
It actually starts with the main character being born.
Desmond had to feel that. No more Holy Land, it's time for Renaissance Italy or specifically
Firenze (Florence), Monteriggioni and Venezia (Venice).
And yes, I did do the hand thing while saying those names. In modern time
Kristen Bell helps Desmond escape. They are going to use the machine to turn him into a parkour pro!
How will this HTC vive chair train his muscles?
No one? You play as Ezio Auditore da Firenze, who has everything, then he gets betrayed and now
seeks vengeance. I bet this is the only game where they are going to use that plot. Then Ezio gets vengeance thirty minutes later
Good for him. Back in modern times, Desmond has learned how to jump! Couldn't do that before, good for him.
Then he starts to hallucinate and....
(The biggest nightmare of AC2 players)
Back in Italy, Ezio decides to pretend other people wronged him so he can get some more vengeance!
And let's just say the final boss is a fistfight with the Pope and no other game has yet to beat that. Then in the Pope
Basement he finds a- listen up
now: a member of an ancient race that created
humanity and also the Pieces of Eden and also the world is ending and also you need to fix this. Then she talks to the
camera and says
"Desmond". I played this at 2:00 a.m
On a school night, it blew my mind so I couldn't sleep. I blame this game for my academic failings
But this is very exciting. I wonder what's gonna happen in Assassin's Creed 3...
Assassin's Creed 3- No!
What's this? Assassin's Creed 2 sold too many copies, Ubisoft can no longer be the shovelware company
They had found their Call of Duty, so they had to add multiplayer. To make Brotherhood,
they took a copy of Assassin's Creed 2, used a grinder on it and it was done. And I love it.
It introduced a new concept: an actual villain. Cesare Borgia,
who was a Spanish person that took control of Italy and did what a Spanish person in control of Italy would do. The story is:
Ezio has it all, uh oh
Time for vengeance! In modern time, the gang brings an expensive delicate supercomputer to a dusty tomb.
That's all they do. New feature: recruit assassins. You do this by finding people surrounded by guards, and murder the officers.
This is an insane way to recruit people and explains so much about the assassins. If I saw someone surrounded by police, I wouldn't be like: that guy who's clearly off his meds should join my secret order!
It ends with Ezio getting vengeance. In modern times, the gang visits the Coliseum. There they meet the second biggest bad of the franchise:
Juno, the first one being jumping mechanics. They get the Apple of Eden, Kristen Bell makes a pun about apple pie
of Eden, so Desmond stabs her to death. Well deserved. The point is you can drive a tank, solid 10/10. Assassin's Creed-
Ok now you're pushing it. Desmond wakes up in that stuck in a game trope, typical anime. There
he meets the symbol drawer and he tells Desmond to leave the game
you have to make Ubisoft a bit more money using the old game engine. Welcome to
Constantinople, Ezio is old but still ripped. You can also play as Altair!
Remember him? New feature tower defense...
Uh, and uh
I've been staring at this document for two days now. I have nothing interesting to say about Revelations.
I feel like that describes the game good enough. It ends with the Mongols attacking so Altair sits down and dies. (RIP)
Should have been a Genghis Khan fistfight with the song playing
But this isn't a good game. Then a third ancient race guy reveals...
Stuff we already know. (10k people dead in a supernova)
You three need to communicate.
Assassin's Creed
Fuck yeah! Freedom is the only way yeah!
The Ezio trilogy made billions, and finally a true sequel. Did it live up to the hype?
No. New exotic location!
Massachusetts...?
Alright. "Hello. What is the biggest gaming market in the world? Ya serious?
United States. That's the new game's location!" And what US time here it would make the perfect game?
1930s Chicago, but not enough haystacks.
So they moved it back a couple of years so that we can experience the truth behind thE mOSt GrUesOME wAr iN hiSTorY!
Is it though?
Starts out great,
a mature mysterious character, how new and interesting! Okay, one sentence, that's all it took to ruin the game. You actually play as Ratonhnhaké:ton,
they give him an English name, too
but am I supposed to remember two names? People like these randomly generated masses,
but what if we gave their personalities to a main character?
See him grow up and kill his dad's friends, then hang out with traitors of the Crown
What's going on in modern times? I have no idea. Honestly, the entire story is too confusing
There's like a war between Yanks and Brits. They speak the same language. Why are they fighting? There's one symbolic scene
where you tip tea into the ocean because Americans love to tip.
But did they seriously start a war over how to pay waiters? I never finished the game. So don't spoil who wins-
Actually replaying it now six years later. It's not as bad as I remember. And Desmond stops the world from ending,
but then he dies, and so does the modern setting.
Assassin's Creed 4: Johnny just leave her already! Like they had no idea what to do after Desmond's death, in the fourth game
they took the first thing they can think of. You just walk around Ubisoft Montreal, if they got to keep the Assassin's Creed money.
Assassin's Creed 4 came about when Ubi said: "this might sound a bit biased what they really liked about the last game was
killing Englishmen, but you should also be able to kill Spaniards." And they were so tired of this Assassin's Creed shit so
they were like fuck it. Let's make a pirate game, but some sneaky in it.
So now Assassin's Creed 4 is a game about running around looking for papers to get more songs for your boats.
And it's amazing. You play as Edward Kenway. He is a human in the Caribbean
so he turns to piracy. Edward meets famous pirates
like Blackbeard, and less famous pirates like the rest of them (Charles Vane, Benjamin Hornigold, Jack Rackham).
Then the assassins show up and ask Edward if he wants to join their club and Edward says "No.
What, you serious? No!" Making the game actually
Assassin's Creed? No, thanks. I'm fine. I don't even remember what happens
I just remember sailing around having fun. 10/10. It ends with Edward meeting his daughter and they sail away happy
What's this wholesomeness in my mind fuck games? Back at Ubi HQ:
How long until that France game? A year and a half maybe? Okay.
Release it tomorrow. Unity, against Assassin's Creed Unity.
(No joke this game is bad)
During France's Reign of Terror, thousands of innocent people were murdered,
but that is nothing compared to what Unity did to France!
Unity is the worst Assassin's Creed by far. In it, you play as brie cheese
They asked him to join the assassin sneak anticline because cheese doesn't have opinions
He's in love with a girl, but she's a Templar and he's a dairy product!
Everything is boring and uninteresting, but that wouldn't be a problem if it weren't for the English accents!
Accents! The only reason we wanted a game set in France! How bad is it Killian?
Do they call wine and cheese tea and crumpets?
I wouldn't know because in this game about France not a single person drinks wine!
Giving everyone English accents is the biggest design flaw in gaming history!
If the accent irks you so much, why not play with the french dub? Guess what?
They still have English accents in the French version.
Oi je m'appelle Napoleon.
Aw, sacre bleu ain't it?
How did this happen? I think it's because Ubisoft Montreal is
French-canadian so they try to make it seem that only Canada speaks French
I mean even the cash-grab had French accents. Assassin's Creed 4 Winter Edition. So Ubi was having a not-so-great
2014 and not everyone had bought a PS4 yet or a...
PS4 White. In a very cash grab move, they threw together a Templar game, and I love it.
It's not a bit better than Unity. It's like a 100 times better! You play as Shay, an Assassin that turns Templar and...
it's weird playing as the good guys. They are so
wholesome they buy each other ale. The game starts with him hanging out with his Assassin friends and as you expect
Portugal explodes. So he decides to betray his friends. Now you spend the rest of the game hunting down people
you've built a relationship with. Every target is someone you know (Rip Adewalé).
It ends with you completely destroying the assassin Brotherhood in North America and
killing the brie cheese maker. It's the happiest ending in Assassin's Creed history! Assassin's Creed
Wait, what? There was an assassin's Creed between unity and Origins? Did you guys know this? Syndicate is set in London
I used up all my English jokes on Unity, now
I have to actually talk about the game. During the Victorian era,
Templars have turned Britain into a superpower! Time to stop that. Pick between Evie, an educated archaeologist and
Jacob, who probably can't read. New feature, levels! And they brought
Button-mashing in from the Batman games and the grappling hook so you don't have to climb in this climbing simulator
It ends with a terrible boss fight and then they tried to resurrect a modern
timeline and they failed. I only play as Evie because I don't trust Jacob, because...
Jacob- short that to Jac,
Victorian England- Jack the Ripper! "Now you're reaching, Killian." Guess what?
It's canon! There was DLC where Jacob is chasing the Ripper and in a surprise twist
Jacob actually turned into Jack the Ripper, then in a very dark moment for series
the sister now has to kill her beloved brother, and that's how you kill a main character!
None of this father issue bullshit. The game is actually well liked among the people that bought it. Those five people loved it,
but Ubisoft wanted at least twice as many sales. So the franchise took a year off. Assassin's Creed's Uplay
They announced the earliest game ever, set in ancient Egypt. So that was a lie!
Ancient Egypt doesn't have enough celebrities Assassin's Creed origins takes place in ptolemaic
Egypt, you play as Bayek and yes, we are already on the revenge plot faster than ever.
The games are now RPGs inspired by The Witcher, Bayek has to kill members of the mask
Then he becomes a background character for season 1 of Rome. Protip:
Skip all the cutscenes just watch season 1. The game actually ends with you playing as Bayek's wife and you kill the most
beloved person in the world- what have you done?! You just killed
ancient Tom Hanks. Ah, we all know what happens next. I shall now recite the entire famous Marc Anthony speech
"Friends, Romans, countrymen, lend me your ears;
I've come to say that backstabbing is a bitch-ass move, everybody riot!" Then she tells Cleopatra that fucking up was kind of fun
I'm gonna start a club and that's gonna be our thing.
We just gonna quit we're gonna fuck up throughout history the Assassin Brotherhood. Most fans like Origins,
not me because I played the game as a stealth game and there's way less- Okay, you caught me
I'm not over the fact that it's not ancient Egypt
I wanted one scene: Bayek meets a random NPC and he says "Hi
I'm just a random guy. Not a famous person." "Hi random guy" then hours later
"Hi Bayek, I'm actually a famous person." "Whaaaaat?
no!" "My name is
Moses!" "OOOOOH
SHIT!" "Wanna see something cool?"
"Yeah!" "You see that pond over there?" "OH SHIT HE'S GONNA DO THE THING!"
Never happened. 0/10. Assassin's Creed copyrights Homer 600 BC
I asked an Ubi employee where the next Assassin's Creed was gonna take place and she said Greece. I did not see that
coming but that's a perfect twist for the franchise. Then the first picture gets leaked and I was like
They said ancient Greece. So I expected it to take place in like the 90s or something.
But no, actual ancient Greece. You play as religious Ezio or Cassandra.
They were thrown off a cliff and now they seek vengeance. On someone else. Man,
Greece was fancy before the invention of cigarettes.
I haven't finished it yet, but I'm guessing it ends with him bringing peace to Greece.
Then he says I like peace and I like temples
I must start a peace club called the Templars. The gang shows upand they sing: "Tell me more, Tell me more!"
I kind of like the game, but quests do get repetitive and microtransactions
20 euros for twenty thousand money
It takes like 30 minutes to get that much money, but they will also keep this franchise running forever. I think
the next game is going to take place in China because "mArKeT's So BiG!"
But what I really want is a game where you play as a Templar and you travel to colleges and destroy
Assassins with facts and science. And that is the Templar Killian experience